<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>cartography on Thoughts - Ambarish</title>
    <link>/tags/cartography/</link>
    <description>Recent content in cartography on Thoughts - Ambarish</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© Copyright notice</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 04 Apr 2018 02:01:58 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/cartography/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Kiva Kernel Award</title>
      <link>/awards/2018-04-04-kiva-kernels-award/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Apr 2018 02:01:58 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/awards/2018-04-04-kiva-kernels-award/</guid>
      <description>Kiva.org is an online crowdfunding platform to extend financial services to poor and financially excluded people around the world. Kiva lenders have provided over $1 billion dollars in loans to over 2 million people. In order to set investment priorities, help inform lenders, and understand their target communities, knowing the level of poverty of each borrower is critical. However, this requires inference based on a limited set of information for each borrower.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Themed Kernel Award Winner - Spooky EDA</title>
      <link>/awards/2017-12-25-spooky-eda/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Dec 2017 02:01:58 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/awards/2017-12-25-spooky-eda/</guid>
      <description>Kaggle organized a Halloween playground competition, in which Text Miners were challenged to predict the author of excerpts from horror stories by Edgar Allan Poe, Mary Shelley, and HP Lovecraft.
Prizes were given for most upvoted kernels, most upvoted discussions and themed kernels such as Python Tutorial, R Tutorial, Creative Feature Engineering and Creative Data Visualization. Honoured to receive the R Tutorial prize for the kernel Tutorial:Detailed Spooky Fun EDA and Modelling</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>African Conflicts</title>
      <link>/posts/2017-10-17-african-conflicts/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0030</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2017-10-17-african-conflicts/</guid>
      <description>We examine a dataset from ACLED(Armed Conflict Location and Event Project).The Armed Conflict Location and Event Data Project is designed for disaggregated conflict analysis and crisis mapping. This dataset codes the dates and locations of all reported political violence and protest events in dozens of developing countries in Africa. Political violence and protest includes events that occur within civil wars and periods of instability, public protest and regime breakdown. The project covers all African countries from 1997 to the present.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Austin Bike Share EDA with Maps and TimeSeries</title>
      <link>/posts/2017-10-07-austin-bikeshare/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0030</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2017-10-07-austin-bikeshare/</guid>
      <description>Catching a show on Red River? Eating on the East Side? Paddleboarding at Zilker? All of the above?
Hop on a B-cycle and coast your way through the People’s Republic of Austin
We explore the Austin Bike Share data for the following topics :
 Top 10 Common Start Stations Top 10 Common Destination Stations Get Top 10 Most Popular Routes Map of Bike Stations Month , Day , Time Analysis Types of Subscriber Month , Day , Time Analysis for Local365 Duration of Trips Trips for Station ID #2575 BikeTrips for Station ID #2575 (Week wise) SXSW 2017 SXSW 2016  A detailed report Austin Bike Share Analysis has the complete Data Visualization with Maps.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meteorite Landings</title>
      <link>/posts/2017-10-05-meteorite-landings/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0030</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2017-10-05-meteorite-landings/</guid>
      <description>We examine a dataset from NASA Meteorite Landings and do a complete Exploratory Data Analysis.
The Meteoritical Society collects data on meteorites that have fallen to Earth from outer space. This dataset includes the location, mass, composition, and fall year for over 45,000 meteorites that have struck our planet.
A detailed report Fun with Meteorite Landings has the complete Exploratory Data Analysis.
A book on this report can be found in Little Book on Exploratory Data Analysis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Crime in Los Angeles</title>
      <link>/posts/2017-09-25-la-crime/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0030</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2017-09-25-la-crime/</guid>
      <description>We investigate the Crime in LA. We do Exploratory Data analysis on various topics such as the Month of Crime ,Day of Crime,Time of Crime. We also explore how the Crimes are related to the Sex and Age of the Victims, Crime Types, Crime Types of persons aged 70 and above. We explore on the Crimes at different Premises,Types of Crimes at different Premises,victim Descent Analysis and an analysis of Weapons used in Crime.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly Kaggle Kernel Award Winner - African Conflicts</title>
      <link>/awards/2017-08-18-weekly-kernel-winner-african-conflicts-copy/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Aug 2017 02:01:58 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/awards/2017-08-18-weekly-kernel-winner-african-conflicts-copy/</guid>
      <description>We examine a dataset from ACLED(Armed Conflict Location and Event Project).The Armed Conflict Location and Event Data Project is designed for disaggregated conflict analysis and crisis mapping. This dataset codes the dates and locations of all reported political violence and protest events in dozens of developing countries in Africa. Political violence and protest includes events that occur within civil wars and periods of instability, public protest and regime breakdown. The project covers all African countries from 1997 to the present.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
