<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>statistics on Thoughts - Ambarish</title>
    <link>/tags/statistics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in statistics on Thoughts - Ambarish</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© Copyright notice</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 10 Sep 2021 10:00:00 +0030</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/statistics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Binomial Distributions</title>
      <link>/posts/binomial-distributions/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Sep 2021 10:00:00 +0030</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/binomial-distributions/</guid>
      <description>Binomial Probability distribution has the following characteristics:
  A fixed number of trials n. e.g., 20 coin toss , 40 students
  A binary outcome, a success and a failure. Probability of success is p, probability of failure is 1-p. e.g., head or tail in a coin toss , pass or fail of sttudents in an exam, positive and negative results of a test of a patient.
  Constant probability for each trial.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Discrete and Continuous Probability distribution</title>
      <link>/posts/discrete-continous-distributions/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Sep 2021 00:04:00 +0030</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/discrete-continous-distributions/</guid>
      <description>We continue our discussion of the Discrete and Continuous Probability distribution.
Blood Types - Discrete distribution function Here we present the distribution of different Blood Types
   # x p     1 O 45%   2 A 40%   3 B 11%   4 AB 4%    Emergency Room probability distribution function The number of patients seen in an Emergency Room in any given hour is provided by a random variable x</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Probability Distributions</title>
      <link>/posts/probability-distributions/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0030</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/probability-distributions/</guid>
      <description>Probability distribution is also known as Probability function.
 This gives the probabilities of all possible outcomes A mathematical function which maps each possible outcome x to the probability p(x) The probabilities must all sum or integrate to 1  Discrete and Continous Probability distribution Discrete probability functions can take only discrete values. Examples include Dead/ Alive , numbers obtained by rolling a die, treatment / placebo, whole numbers
Continuous probability functions can take any value within a range.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>activation functions</title>
      <link>/posts/2017-07-06-activation-functions/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0030</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2017-07-06-activation-functions/</guid>
      <description>Sigmoid function takes values between 0 and 1
$ {sigmoid} = \frac {e^x} {( 1+ e^x )} $
This is used in logistic regression.
The sigmoid graph is generated by the R code provided below.
Softmax function is used to calculate the probablities in multiple classes. Suppose we have a image of a digit. We want to calculate whether it is a 1, 2, 3, and so on. Softmax would provide the probablity for each of the classes.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
