<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Courses on Thoughts - Ambarish</title>
    <link>/courses/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Courses on Thoughts - Ambarish</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© Copyright notice</copyright><atom:link href="/courses/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Intro to Deep Learning</title>
      <link>/courses/intro-to-deep-learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/courses/intro-to-deep-learning/</guid>
      <description>Topic Description Video Link     01- single neuron This video introduces the concept of the simplest neural network, the single neuron Single Neuron   01-exercise single neuron This video explains step by step the exercise on the single neuron. Gain more clarity by doing this exercise. Exercise Single Neuron   02-deep neural network This video explains a simple deep neural network , activation functions , hidden layers Deep Neural Network   02- exercise deep neural network This video explains the step by step exercise on simple deep neural network , activation functions , hidden layers Exercise Deep Neural Network   03 - Stochastic Gradient Descent This video explains the concept of optimizer , loss function , stochastic gradient descent Stochastic Gradient Descent   03 - exercise Stochastic Gradient Descent In this exercise we will train a neural network on the Fuel Economy dataset and then explore the effect of the learning rate and batch size on SGD Exercise Stochastic Gradient Descent   04 - Overfitting and Underfitting This video explains the concept of Overfitting and Underfitting Overfitting and Underfitting   04 - exercise Overfitting and Underfitting In this exercise, we will learn how to improve training outcomes by including an early stopping callback to prevent overfitting Exercise Overfitting and Underfitting   05 - Dropout and BatchNormalization This video explains the concept of Dropout and BatchNormalization to prevent overfitting and help in making the training more stable Dropout and BatchNormalization   05 - exercise Dropout and BatchNormalization In this exercise, we will add dropout to the Spotify model from Exercise 4 and see how batch normalization can let us successfully train models on difficult datasets.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
